[ELLIOTT]
Blast it!
Every one of them is drenched!
Oh, no.
How can this be?
The roof's leaking.
How did we not notice it?
No one knew
that it would rain so much.
It's unusual
for this time of year.
[ANNE]
If it's all ruined,
we won't finish in time
for the festival!
[rain falling]
Don't cry,
Miss Head of Artisans.
So, what now? [gasps]
We will figure something out.
[gasps] Right!
[clatters]
Then let's grind it again!
First, we'll move
all the silver sugar
into the hearth room
to dry it out!
Can someone go
and get the mortars
from the workroom?
And quickly!
No matter what, let's be done
by the end of the day!
[KING, NADIR, VALENTINE, ORLAND]
Right!
[footsteps]
[rain falling]
The sugar! Is it safe?
[sighs]
It's worse than I feared.
I knew the castle
was damaged in places,
but I wasn't expecting all this.
You're regrinding it?
I can have my school send more.
Or perhaps
the Radcliffe workshop
could spare some.
[ELLIOTT]
Don't be silly,
you know we could never ask
for that.
Can you finish then?
I have no doubt.
[HUGH]
Good work, everyone!
But tomorrow's the real battle.
Get some rest for now.
♪
[sighs]
The rain finally stopped.
Looks that way.
If we give it the whole night
to dry out,
then we can grind some tomorrow.
Let me look after the hearth,
all right?
Why don't you go
and get some sleep?
I can't do that.
You should!
I wouldn't want
to be ungentlemanlike.
Yes,
but I'm the Head of Artisans.
Hm. All right, fine.
We'll take turns.
Do you think...
we can finish everything
before time?
[sighs] It's hard to say.
Despite what I told
the Viscount,
I'm not all that confident.
Even after the silver sugar
is reground,
we'll still need time
to create the pieces
and assemble them.
If only we had
one more skilled artisan
on the team...
Do you think Kieth would come
lend us a hand?
[ELLIOTT]
Never!
Mr. Radcliffe
wouldn't allow him to.
That's just how tribalism works.
[ANNE sighs]
[ANNE] I know,
but there must be someone else!
A capable artisan
who doesn't belong to a school.
[ANNE, ELLIOTT]
Oh! There's Kat!
[ELLIOTT]
He's in Southcent at the moment,
running a shop.
I doubt he's got many customers.
If you ask him,
I'm sure he'll help us!
[ANNE]
Good!
Then we should all be back
by evening!
And I'll keep an eye on Noah
for you.
[ANNE]
Thank you!
- [CHALLE] Let's go.
- [ANNE] Right!
- [horse neighs]
- [hoofbeats]
[sighs]
[footsteps]
They're all so cold to you.
Despite how deeply worried
you are for them.
I'm used to it, really.
[whimpers]
♪
He's never tried very hard
to attract business.
[CHALLE] Well,
it's better than last time.
[snoring softly]
- [door creaks]
- [ANNE] Excuse us.
- Huh? Uh...
- [door slams]
It's good to see you, Benjamin.
[BENJAMIN]
That's funny.
You look just like Anne.
I am Anne.
It's been a long time.
Oh, hello!
What brings you
to a place like this?
I came to ask something of Kat
if he's here.
Is he?
Yes, indeed! [grunts]
Kat? There's a pretty girl here
to see you!
[door creaks]
Say I'm busy!
- Oh, it's you two! Hm.
- [door creaks]
So, you got Challe back?
[ANNE] Yes. Thank you so much
for all your help.
There's no need to thank me
since I didn't do anything.
Did you come all this way
just to say that?
[ANNE] No, actually,
I need a favor.
Favor?
[ANNE]
Well, currently,
I'm working
as the Head of Artisans
at the Paige Workshop.
Ooh, how prestigious!
You've really done well!
You see,
we're creating all the pieces
for the Holy Beginnings
Festival.
We started working
in Holly Leaf Castle, and then--
I'm familiar with that place, actually.
The rain, right?
Yes. The silver sugar's ruined.
We're doing our best
to regrind it.
But now,
it's put you behind schedule,
so you're hoping
I'll lend you a hand
with the sugar confections,
aren't you?
Would that be possible, Kat?
It won't.
I only make the things
I want to make.
Besides,
I've got a birthday order
for the old flour shop lady
after the New Year.
And I'll prioritize her
over anything else,
the king and the church.
Isn't there anything
that you can do?
Without your help, we'll fail!
I already said no, so no!
Say, Mister Kat--
- Challe!
- Really?
I hate being called
"Mister Kat",
did you forget that?
I remember.
- [ANNE sighs]
- [grunts] That was purposeful?
Yes. Purposeful.
You must be looking for a fight!
Wait,
please don't kill each other!
Now then, Mister Kat.
I understand
that you owe a favor
to the Viscount.
[gasps]
[VISCOUNT] I told Kat,
when I talked to you,
that you would say something
along those lines.
Even then,
he wouldn't back down,
so I decided
we should make it a wager.
He bet you'd want me
to get involved,
and I bet you wouldn't.
And now that he's lost,
the penalty
is that I have a chance
to force him
to do anything I say.
Now that you mention it,
that is true.
No, I don't owe a single thing
to that dimwitted reprobate!
That was just a joke!
A mere blunder! [grunts]
And that favor,
did he redeem it yet?
Well, actually...
Is the deal complete?
No.
Hm?
[gasps] That's it!
If we can persuade him
to surrender his request,
do you think you would be
more willing to help us?
- You can do that?
- Yes!
I'm certain he would hand it off
to me instead!
Please, I'd be so grateful
if you'd come help us work!
[sighs] I don't know.
The Holy Beginnings Festival
isn't only for the royals
or the kingdom's religion
because it's a time of prayer
for the happiness
of all those who live here!
And if our confections are good,
we'll have good luck!
Which means that we won't have
a bad sugar apple harvest
like we did this year!
Hm... Hm...
Well, I'd rather do that
than whatever he wants.
So yes?
Hm.
I'll do it!
- [hoofbeats]
- [ANNE] Thank you, Challe!
I'm glad you reminded me
of what Hugh said before!
[CHALLE]
You and Kat are both idiots,
so the conversation
wasn't progressing.
[chuckles]
[ANNE]
Even so...
it made me really happy that
Challe helped me with something.
Oh? There they are!
- [door slams]
- Oh! Great to see you!
Huh?
So, what happened with Kat?
Hugh!
The right to have Kat
do anything you say,
please give it to me!
Sorry? [sighs]
I suppose that means
he turned you down, eh?
But he also said that he'd help
if I surrendered the right
to that favor.
[gasps]
That's exactly right.
So, if you please.
I need it!
I refuse.
When Kat creates
a sugar confection,
it's because he actually wants
to do it.
And now, I have a chance
to make him do anything!
But Kat is our only hope
to get through this!
Well, I have no intention
of spoiling you that much.
If you want it that badly,
pry it away from me.
Fine, I will.
Really?
Are you proposing that we duel?
You know,
there are rules about that.
The Silver Sugar Viscount
is only allowed
to make confections
that are ordered by the king.
That said there is an exception
for contests.
[ANNE]
Hm...
[pats]
Huh?
Mm.
Let's compete!
[SALIM]
A reckless move.
You're kidding.
[huffs]
Very well, Halford.
We have a match.
You versus me.
And the judge?
Let me see,
I heard there's a fairy here
who's been starving himself
to death.
I say whoever manages
to feed him is the winner.
Noah? Hm...
All right then!
He'll be the judge!
Good!
I'll need my tools
and silver sugar by tomorrow!
Bring some for Anne, as well,
Salim!
Sir.
Did you hear all that, Collins?
I'll be staying here with you.
Make yourself at home then.
Best of luck, Anne.
[MITHRIL]
What?
You versus the Viscount?
He'll mop the floor with you!
[ANNE] Well,
we don't know that for sure.
[MITHRIL, ELLIOTT sigh]
Sorry, but it's too much.
Starting work on it today
and then feeding it to him
tomorrow?
Pardon me, Anne.
I'm going back
to the hearth now.
Can you at least be the one
to tell the others?
I'm afraid
I don't have the heart to do it.
[whimpers]
[rumbling]
[NADIR, VALENTINE grunting]
[KING, ORLAND grunting]
[footsteps]
[ARTISANS grunting]
Everyone.
Anne! [sighs]
Here, put some of this
on your hands!
Your blisters are bursting!
[VALENTINE]
That looks painful!
Listen, there's something
I need to tell you.
[NADIR]
Oh, we know. Elliott told us.
[NADIR, MITHRIL chuckle]
Don't worry.
We'll leave it to you.
And in the meantime,
we can cover your portion
of the work!
Allow us to handle
everything else, Anne.
You can just concentrate
on winning.
Perfectly said!
Let's stay strong to the end!
Right?
[NADIR, ORLAND, VALENTINE]
Right!
[gasps]
[ANNE]
This is my job.
I have to succeed!
Not just for my own sake,
but for all of theirs, as well!
He's so weak.
I truly hope he'll eat.
He might refuse
to accept either one.
I know.
But maybe that was why
Hugh suggested this.
He's confident
that he can do it.
Fairies love sugar confections,
but does the shape or design
make a difference?
If the shape has special meaning
for you,
the fragrance and beauty of it
will be magnified.
So, it makes you want
to hold it close
much in the same way you long
to kiss someone you love.
[ANNE] I wonder
if there's anything in life
that means as much to Noah
as Lord Herbert does.
- [rustle]
- Go to sleep.
You'll need all your strength.
You too.
I'll watch over him.
But Challe,
you can't stay up
the whole night!
Your competition's important.
But still... [gasps]
[CHALLE]
What's wrong?
Do you need
another goodnight kiss?
I'll give you one if I must.
Sleep.
[ANNE]
Um, good night, Challe!
[door creaks and slams]
[SALIM]
Viscount,
Anne has arrived
with your breakfast.
I see
that you've made a mess again.
- [footsteps]
- [thuds]
Haven't I asked you before
to treat books with more care?
And the fathers
who lent them to you,
they had requested
the same thing.
I'm the one
who has to return them
if you remember.
That isn't what they meant
when they told me to be careful.
They just wanted me
to keep them hidden.
If I weren't in the peerage,
I wouldn't be able to read
any of these.
They're what you would call
"banned books".
Those are banned? Why?
What's bad about them?
I can't share secrets
with my opponent, now can I?
So, your subject
did you choose one?
Um, well, no.
[HUGH]
There's not much time.
[ANNE]
I know.
By the way, Anne,
I have a visit to pay
as soon as breakfast is over.
♪
Noah, are you awake now?
There's someone
who'd like a word with you.
[whimpers]
[sighs]
[HUGH]
Pardon me.
I'm Silver Sugar Viscount
Hugh Mercury.
What?
Oh, I wasn't expecting you, sir.
[straining]
You can relax.
May I ask you a question, please?
Huh?
Your master Herbert,
was he an asset to his house
and a decent man?
Yes.
I hear he liked
the game of fief.
Hm, well, I shouldn't say this,
but truth be told,
he wasn't exactly good at it.
Huh?
He was bad at fief, you say?
Right.
That's why
he really only ever played it
with me.
Hm. I see.
Well, that's all, get some rest.
I'll bring you
something nice later
- to say thank you.
- [sighs]
[ANNE] Something
that holds meaning for him.
Something he would eat.
If I recreate
Lord Herbert's likeness
as a confection,
that might make him happy.
Like with the Duke of Philax.
But...
[footsteps]
[GLADUS]
I hear you're competing
- with the Silver Sugar Viscount.
- Huh?
♪
- Ah...
- Are you scared?
Is that
because of Challe fenn Challe?
He told you
to stay away from me?
Well, that's not exactly it.
[gasps]
Hm. There's no reason to worry.
I would consider myself
extremely close to him.
But it's impossible
to read his true intentions.
I can't get him to open up.
You're close?
That's right.
And I have no ill intent
toward him
or anything
that he holds precious,
nor do I desire
to do him any harm.
Anne.
- The truth is we two--
- [door slams]
What's going on in here?
- [gasps]
- Hm.
- [footsteps]
- Nothing at all.
Just having a conversation
with Anne
about her upcoming competition
with the Viscount.
Truly?
You against him?
You're kidding.
It's the only way.
[exhales]
[scoffs]
There's no chance you'll win.
So why try?
Ah!
We're leaving, Gladus.
Right. Take care, Anne.
[footsteps]
That was bizarre.
[CHALLE] I'm amazed
you're still staring at that.
Have you thought of something?
Mm-mm. Not at all.
All I can think about
is how bad Noah must feel.
Looking at this old portrait
and missing his master.
Poor thing.
[footsteps]
[CHALLE] There must be something
we can't see.
Something only Noah is aware of.
[ANNE]
Something we can't see?
That's true.
If all he wanted to do
was remember the past,
then he wouldn't have to sit
in this spot.
There has to be something
about this portrait,
but no matter how hard I look...
I'm still not seeing it.
♪
- [flaps]
- [footsteps]
Say, Challe?
Please take it off the wall,
- would you?
- [CHALLE] Of course.
- [thuds]
- [crunching]
Oh...
[gasps]
♪
[CHALLE]
That looks like...
[ANNE] I think
it's the Crest of House Chamber!
The royals tried
to destroy them all,
but they missed this one.
And Noah knew it was here.
He must've been trying
to guard it.
A crest is the pride
of a noble house,
and this is the last one.
It's Lord Herbert's spirit
in physical form.
This is what
Noah was looking at!
[exhales]
Challe,
I know what I'm going to create.
Huh?
This crest is taboo.
The Millsland royal family
erased it from existence.
And you plan to resurrect it?
Despite your position?
It's risky.
As a silver sugar master,
I shouldn't defy the crown.
But then what's the harm
in people seeing
House Chamber's crest?
Everyone who bore it
is gone now.
I'm not making
this sugar confection
for the royal family.
I'm making it for the person
who needs it the most.
Because that's what it means
to be a sugar artisan,
don't you think so?
If there's even one person
who might want it,
then that's reason enough!
You're bold, aren't you?
Defying the royal family.
I'm not trying
to make people angry,
even if they might think
that I am.
But at this point,
I can't change my mind!
[sighs]
Well, then,
make what you want to make.
- [gasps]
- No matter what comes of it,
I will always protect you.
And...
I'll stay by your side.
[clatters]
[water trickling]
[ANNE]
Challe's looking after me.
♪